It's on in the Amazon.
Rio 2 is a animation, adventure, comedy film directed by Carlos Saldanha.
It's a jungle out there for Blu, Jewel and their three kids after they're
hurtled from Rio de Janeiro to the wilds of the Amazon.
As Blu tries to fit in, he goes beak-to-beak with the vengeful Nigel, and
meets the most fearsome adversary of all: his father-in-law.
Blu (voice), played by Jesse Eisenberg.
Jewel (voice), played by Anne Hathaway.
Pedro (voice), played by will.i.am.
Nico (voice), played by Jamie Foxx.
Linda (voice), played by Leslie Mann.
Rafael (voice), played by George López.
Rio 2 is a 2014 American animated musical comedy film directed by Carlos Saldanha and
written by Don Rhymer, Carlos Kotkin, Jenny Bicks, and Yoni Brenner.
The sequel to Rio (2011), it was produced by Blue Sky Studios.
The film features Anne Hathaway, Jesse Eisenberg, Jemaine Clement, Leslie Mann, George Lopez, Jamie Foxx, will.i.am, Tracy Morgan, and Rodrigo Santoro
reprising their roles from the first film, with Kristin Chenoweth, Bruno Mars, Rita Moreno, Andy Garcia, and Miguel Ferrer joining the cast.
Set three years after the events of the first film, it follows Blu, Jewel, and their children leaving Rio for the
Amazon rainforest to find other blue macaws, while Nigel the cockatoo pursues them to exact revenge.
Rio 2 was released internationally on March 20, 2014, and on
April 11 the United States, by 20th Century Fox.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $499
million against a budget of $103–130 million.
A third film is in development.
The film explores themes of villain, amazon rainforest, sequel, travel, jungle.
The tone is lighthearted.